Still the man, any questions?
Shaft is a action, adventure, crime film directed by John Singleton.
New York police detective John Shaft arrests Walter Wade Jr.
for a racially motivated slaying.
But the only eyewitness disappears, and Wade jumps bail for Switzerland.
Two years later Wade returns to face trial, confident his money and influence will get him
acquitted -- especially since he's paid a drug kingpin to kill the witness.
John Shaft, played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Carmen Vasquez, played by Vanessa Williams.
Peoples Hernandez, played by Jeffrey Wright.
Walter Wade, Jr., played by Christian Bale.
Rasaan, played by Busta Rhymes.
Jack Roselli, played by Dan Hedaya.
Shaft is a 2000 American action crime thriller film co-written,
co-produced, and directed by John Singleton and starring Samuel L.
Jackson in the title role with Vanessa Williams, Jeffrey Wright, Christian Bale,
Dan Hedaya, Busta Rhymes, Toni Collette and Richard Roundtree.
It is a sequel to the 1971 Shaft film, in which Jackson plays the nephew
(retconned as his son in the 2019 film) of John Shaft.
The film opened at the number-one position at the box
office when it debuted June 16, 2000.
It received mixed to positive reviews on Metacritic, with the critical
consensus on Rotten Tomatoes praising Jackson's charisma.
The film explores themes of drug dealer, new york city,
corruption, sibling relationship, based on novel or book.
The tone is intense.